<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>AAS Job Register: Pre-doctoral/Graduate Positions</title>
    <description>RSS feed for pre-doctoral/graduate positions offered at the AAS Job Register</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <link>https://aas2rss.pmelchior.net:443/aas2rss.php?channel=graduate</link>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 17:18:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Chaini Interns- #0002225</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JWST has launched! Share in the thrill of space exploration and join our team! The Space Telescope Science Institute (STScI) has openings for paid Interns in our Instruments Division. This is a great opportunity to build practical experience in data analysis and software development for applications in support of space astronomy missions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an INS Intern, you will work with an instrument team in developing software tools and performing analyses to support our flagship missions: the Hubble Space Telescope, the James Webb Space Telescope, and the Nancy Grace Roman Space Telescope. Interns may work up to 20 hours per week, and are available from six months to up to 1 year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who are we looking for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are looking for Baltimore-area undergraduate students who are dedicated, hardworking, eager to learn, and can work with minimum supervision. The opportunity may be ideal for you if you are seeking “outside of the classroom” experiences to further grow professionally in a team setting, if you want to participate in forefront science and have a keen interest in astronomy, and if you want to work in an environment that respects and relies upon the diversity of its staff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This opportunity is geared to majors in computer science, data science, aerospace engineering, physics, or astronomy (or related fields) with an interest in pursuing careers in scientific data analysis. It may build experience in astronomical instrumentation, statistical analysis, scientific programming (especially in python), machine learning methodologies, and utilizing cloud computing services. Previous experience in these areas is desired, but not required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are invited to apply&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applications will be accepted until January 26, 2022. You will need to submit a resume and a cover letter describing your interest, relevant skills, and your availability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please ONLY submit application thru this link:  &lt;a href="https://stsci.slideroom.com/#/permalink/program/65039"&gt;https://stsci.slideroom.com/#/permalink/program/65039&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Space Telescope Science Institute is located on the Johns Hopkins University Homewood Campus. It is expected that at the start of 2022, STScI staff will be working both in the office and from home in a hybrid work environment. However, this may change in response to the COVID-19 crisis. The safety of our staff and community is our top priority. Employees are required to be reside in the local area in case on-site presence is required..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STScI sees the diversity of our staff as a strategic priority in our desire to create a first-rate community. We reflect that deep commitment in strongly encouraging women, minorities, veterans and disabled individuals to apply for these opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Veterans, disabled individuals or wounded warriors needing assistance with the employment process can contact us at &lt;a href="/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#761517041313040536050205151f58131203"&gt;[email protected]&lt;/a&gt;. EOE/AA/M/F/D/V Voted to the Baltimore Magazine Hall of Fame in 2020 – Top 25 Places to Work in Baltimore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Included Benefits:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;p&gt;STScI will ship a computer to your home and provide virtual on-boarding. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Related URLs:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://stsci.slideroom.com/#/permalink/program/65039"&gt;Link to apply&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.stsci.edu/opportunities/our-work/our-culture"&gt;STSci Cutlure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Application Deadline:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Wednesday, January 26, 2022Selection Deadline:Wednesday, January 26, 2022&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Status of Position:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;p&gt;Accepting Applicants</description>
      <link>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/013105da</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2022 07:37:17 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/013105da</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022 Space Astronomy Summer Program (SASP) Intern Positions</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Each summer, the Space Telescope Science Institute (STScI) hires about a dozen highly motivated college students  for the Space Astronomy Summer Program (SASP) to work individually with STScI researchers and staff on projects that include Science Research; Science Instrumentation + Calibration; Science Software Development; and Science Public Outreach. STScI is a premier astronomical research institution, and our scientific staff of astronomers, scientists, analysts, and engineers is at the forefront of some of the most exciting astronomy going on today, including the study of our own solar system, the structure of the Milky Way, the composition of near and distant galaxies, and dark energy.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our virtual program runs June 6th through August 5, 2022, and is primarily open to upper-division undergraduates with a strong interest in space-based astronomy, software engineering, or public outreach (other candidates may be considered on an individual basis). Prior research experience and coding skills are not required. The internship includes a salary of approximately $6,480 and interns will be provided with a computer loan for the duration of the program. Students must be in US to participate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the 2022 SASP interns are matched with a project and a mentor. During your internship, you will meet virtually on a regular basis with your mentor, attend lectures on a wide variety of astronomy and career topics, and interact with other interns and staff, building skills that will help you succeed in STEM fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We proudly partner with the National Astronomy Consortium (NAC) to provide research opportunities to women and underrepresented minorities in astronomy-enterprise areas, and other STEM fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions regarding the application process or the internship, please refer to: &lt;a href="http://www.stsci.edu/opportunities/space-astronomy-summer-program"&gt;http://www.stsci.edu/opportunities/space-astronomy-summer-program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applications must be submitted by 11:59 pm EST January 31, 2022 to receive consideration. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ONLY apply thru this Direct Link:  &lt;a href="https://stsci.slideroom.com/#/permalink/program/65011"&gt;https://stsci.slideroom.com/#/permalink/program/65011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STScI sees the diversity of our staff as a strategic priority in our desire to create a first-rate community. We reflect that deep commitment in strongly encouraging women, minorities, veterans and disabled individuals to apply for these opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Veterans, disabled individuals or wounded warriors needing assistance with the employment process can contact us at &lt;a href="/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#284b495a4d4d5a5b685b5c5b4b41064d4c5d"&gt;[email protected]&lt;/a&gt;. EOE/AA/M/F/D/V Voted to the Baltimore Magazine Hall of Fame – Top 25 Places to Work in Baltimore.&lt;/p&gt;
Pay CompensationStipend:$6480.00 (USD)</description>
      <link>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/4919bbc6</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 18:18:16 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/4919bbc6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PhD opportunity in artificial intelligence and astronomy </title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Astronomy Nucleus at Universidad Diego Portales and INRIA-Chile are seeking for applications for one PhD fellowship to a joint project between astrophysics and artificial intelligence. Once accepted, the applicant will become student of the PhD programme at the Astronomy Nucleus, as well as a member of INRIA-Chile, and is expected to carry out research developing new AI methods aiming to solve an astrophysical problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ph.D. is 4 years long, and students enrolled at UDP are expected to start research activities during their first semester, alongside with specific courses in astrophysics and computer sciences.  The program is offered by UDP’s Astronomy Nucleus, which is characterised by active faculty and an international student body (currently 13 students from 7 different countries). Inria Chile is a research center in digital sciences and technologies, founded by the French Institute for Research in Digital Sciences (INRIA) and is the first and only research center located outside France. World-class research and technological innovation are part of its DNA, having as its mission to conduct and articulate high-impact research and development in digital technologies at the service of society, with special emphasis on Chile and Latin America. It develops research in digital sciences and technologies such as artificial intelligence, deep learning, machine learning, internet of things, optimization, modeling and human-computer interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The selected student will work simultaneously with Paula Jofre from the Astronomy Nucleus and Nayat Sanchez-Pi from INRIA-Chile in a project focused on Galactic archaeology, taking advantage of the large stellar datasets available to the community (Gaia-ESO, GALAH, APOGEE, Gaia, LAMOST, etc). As part of the Chilean community, the student will have beneficial access to all observing facilities in Chile, as well as observing training.  Most crucially for this opportunity, the student will have access to SDSS-V and LSST.   As part of INRIA, the student will benefit from laboratory and computing facilities for getting state-of-the-art training in artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Requirements:&lt;br /&gt;
	Applicants should have an undergraduate and/or master’s degree in Astronomy, statistics, mathematics or computer sciences, full-time commitment, passion for programming, passion for astronomy, passion for interdisciplinary research, and should be fluent in English, which is the official language of the Astronomy Nucleus.&lt;br /&gt;
	 &lt;br /&gt;
	Application materials:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)    Motivation letter (in English) indicating your reasons for applying to the Ph.D. program at UDP specifying where their interest in artificial intelligence comes from, research experience (if any), research interests, and career plans and goals.  Potential applicants are encouraged to contact Paula Jofre (&lt;a href="/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#4434253128256a2e2b2236210429252d286a3120346a2728"&gt;[email protected]&lt;/a&gt;) or Nayat Sanchez-Pi (&lt;a href="/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#533d322a32277d20323d303b36297e233a133a3d213a327d303f"&gt;[email protected]&lt;/a&gt;) for further details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b)   Curriculum Vitae.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;c)   Copy of undergraduate and/or graduate degrees (if already obtained) or letter from University official indicating expected graduation date (if the degree has not been obtained). Accepted applicants will be required to present original or legalized copies of the degrees before registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;d)  Copy of latest academic transcripts available. Accepted applicants will be required to present original or legalized copies of these transcripts before registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;e)   A minimum of two and a maximum of three letters of recommendation sent directly to &lt;a href="/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#6d1d0c18010c4307020b1f082d000c04014318091d430e01"&gt;[email protected]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All application materials (including letters of recommendation) should be submitted by e-mail to &lt;a href="/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#f68697839a97d89c99908493b69b979f9ad8839286d8959a"&gt;[email protected]&lt;/a&gt;.  Applications received by January 15th, 2021 will receive full consideration.  Applicants who submit their applications by this date will be notified of the results around the last week of January 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Financing: Scholarships is available from Inria-Chile to start in March 2021, with  a possibility to start remotely&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Related URLs:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://astronomia.udp.cl/"&gt;Astronomy Nucleus UDP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.inria.cl/en"&gt;INRIA Chile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.paulajofre.com/"&gt;personal website Paula Jofre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Application Deadline:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Saturday, January 15, 2022Selection Deadline:Monday, January 31, 2022&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Status of Position:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;p&gt;Accepting Applicants</description>
      <link>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/26e56044</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 17:39:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/26e56044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summer Research Assistant, Simons-NSBP Scholar</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Flatiron Institute announces a program that provides undergraduate NSBP members with summer research opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	The &lt;a href="https://www.simonsfoundation.org/simons-nsbp-summer-program-snsp/"&gt;Simons-NSBP Scholars Program (SNSP)&lt;/a&gt; is an exciting program that provides undergraduate NSBP members with unparalleled summer research opportunities. The program, which is a partnership between the Simons Foundation, Simons Observatory, and the National Society of Black Physicists, gives its Scholars a holistic experience and provides invaluable training for becoming a professional physicist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Program Description&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SNSP has a number of components that are specifically designed to provide Scholars with the best experience possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Research: SNSP Scholars work on a wide range of projects that have included modeling gravitational waves in the early universe, developing sensors for measuring the Cosmic Microwave Background, and searching for new exoplanets. Each of these projects is at the cutting edge of its field, and our Scholars have been able to make valuable contributions to the projects on which they have worked. This year there will also be Quantum Physics, Biophysics, and Neuroscience projects.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Speaker Series: There are several black physicists working on exciting projects in a variety of areas. Every week of the SNSP, the Scholars hear from a new speaker about their work. The 2021 speaker series featured, among others, Derrick Pitts (Chief Astronomer at the Franklin Institute), Carol Scarlett (Professor of Physics, Florida A&amp;M University) and Delilah Gates (Postdoctoral Scholar, Princeton University).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Professional Development: The SNSP has weekly programming to help Scholars advance their career. These workshops discuss topics ranging from graduate school applications to dealing with imposter syndrome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
	The 2022 SNSP will take place in-person in our New York City offices. Scholars will work on projects with scientists at the Center for Computational Astrophysics, Center for Computational Biology, Center for Computational Quantum Physics, Center for Computational Mathematics, Center for Computational Neuroscience, or Simons Observatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program will start in June 2022 and last for 10 weeks. The 2022 SNSP will kick off with an Opening Ceremony and an intense five-day programming boot camp.&lt;br /&gt;
	 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compensation&lt;br /&gt;
	Simons-NSBP Scholars will receive compensation. Additionally, housing will be provided. Details about housing will be sent closer to the program start date. Finally, all travel and lodging expenses for the Opening Ceremony will be covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Required Application Materials&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
	Applicants to the 2022 SNSP must submit the materials listed below. For full consideration, materials should be received by January 1; however, applications will be considered until all positions are filled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Provide a personal statement stating why you are applying to the SNSP. This can be a statement about your interest in one area of the program (Astrophysics/Cosmology, Biology, Quantum Physics, Neuroscience), what being a Scholar would mean to you, how you feel the program would benefit you, or anything else that you feel is important for evaluating your application. The statement should be a maximum of one page.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Provide a current CV (or resume).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Provide current, unofficial transcripts for all universities you have attended.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The contact information of two people that will submit letters of recommendation on your behalf.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Scholars will be notified of their selection in March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eligibility&lt;br /&gt;
	The SNSP is open to undergraduate members of the National Society of Black Physicists. We especially encourage applications from (i) students entering the final year of undergraduate studies and/or (ii) students studying in non-graduate degree granting departments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you aren’t yet a member of the NSBP, you can join here: &lt;a href="https://nsbp.org/general/register_member_type.asp"&gt;https://nsbp.org/general/register_member_type.asp&lt;/a&gt;?.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An annual student membership will cost approximately $25; we may be able to explore alternative options for students who may be unable to meet this annual membership fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE SIMONS FOUNDATION'S DIVERSITY COMMITMENT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the greatest ideas and discoveries come from a diverse mix of minds, backgrounds and experiences, and we are committed to cultivating an inclusive work environment. The Simons Foundation actively seeks a diverse applicant pool and encourages candidates of all backgrounds to apply. We provide equal opportunities to all employees and applicants for employment without regard to race, religion, color, age, sex, national origin, sexual orientation, gender identity, genetic disposition, neurodiversity, disability, veteran status or any other protected category under federal, state and local law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Application Deadline:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Thursday, January 13, 2022Selection Deadline:Tuesday, February 1, 2022&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Status of Position:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;p&gt;Accepting Applicants</description>
      <link>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/0931e875</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 17:25:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/0931e875</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PhD positions in Astrophysics and Astroinformatics</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the &lt;a href="https://www.astro.uantof.cl/"&gt;Center of Astronomy&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="http://www.uantof.cl"&gt;Universidad de Antofagasta&lt;/a&gt; (CITEVA) we are seeking enthusiastic students with a passion for understanding the wonders of the Universe to join our new PhD program in Astrophysics and Astroinformatics. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antofagasta, where CITEVA is based, is a large and rapidly expanding coastal city in northern Chile on the edge of the spectacular Atacama desert. In this scenic setting, our doctoral students will join our eight Professors who are involved in cutting-edge investigations on a broad range of topics including stellar systems, galaxies from the Milky Way to the farthest reaches of the universe, and the booming field of Astroinformatics. They will have the much sought-after access to the 10% time on current and future international observatories built in Chile (ESO, Las Campanas, CTIO, Gemini, ALMA, E-ELT, GMT, CTA, etc.) along with SDSS-V and LSST, as well as access to local and national computing facilities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applicants must have an undergraduate or Master’s degree in Astronomy or a related field. The application form and additional information regarding the program &lt;a href="https://www.astro.uantof.cl/educacion/doctorate-in-astrophysics-and-astroinformatics/"&gt;are available on our website&lt;/a&gt;. All materials must be submitted to &lt;a href="/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#ee8f9d9a9c81c08a818d9a819c8f8a81ae9b8f809a8188c08d82"&gt;[email protected]&lt;/a&gt; by January 15. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further information can be obtained from the director of the program, &lt;a href="/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#ff9e8c8b8d90d19b909c8b908d9e9b90bf8a9e918b9099d19c93c08c8a9d959a9c8bc2af97bbdacdcf8f908c968b969091dacdcf9691dacdcfbe8c8b8d908f97868c969c8cdacdcf9e919bdacdcfbe8c8b8d90969199908d929e8b969c8c"&gt;Prof. Médéric Boquien&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Application Deadline:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Saturday, January 15, 2022Selection Deadline:Monday, January 31, 2022&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Status of Position:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;p&gt;Accepting Applicants</description>
      <link>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/3c4af1d6</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 17:39:02 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/3c4af1d6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PhD positions at Armagh Observatory and Planetarium</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Applications are invited for a Postgraduate Research Studentship(s) tenable at Armagh Observatory &amp; Planetarium (AOP) from September/October 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Armagh Observatory and Planetarium, located in Northern Ireland, UK, is an astrophysical research institute founded in 1789.  It has 8 staff astronomers, 4 post-doctoral fellows, 8 PhD students and several visiting astronomers.  Research interests include Solar Physics, Solar-System Science, Stellar, Galactic and Extra-galactic Astrophysics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Candidates must have, or expect to obtain, at least an upper second class honours degree or equivalent, in an appropriate discipline (e.g. Physics, Mathematics, Astronomy or Astrophysics).  Successful candidates will be enrolled at an appropriate university and carry out a research programme primarily based at AOP.  The successful applicants will receive a grant based on the United Kingdom Science and Technology Facilities Council rate (£15,609 per annum in 2021/22) which lasts 3.5 years.  In addition, AOP will fully fund the university fees (irrespective of the applicant’s nationality) and contribute towards the costs of obtaining a UK VISA for international students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prospective candidates should fill in the application form (&lt;a href="https://www.armagh.space/research/phd-programme"&gt;https://www.armagh.space/research/phd-programme&lt;/a&gt;) and ensure that their references as well as any other required additional documents are received on or before the deadline of Friday 28 Jan 2022. First selection will take place as soon as possible after this date with subsequent selections thereafter until all positions have been filled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Application Deadline:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Friday, January 28, 2022&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Status of Position:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;p&gt;Accepting Applicants</description>
      <link>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/32fd9ec0</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 22:15:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/32fd9ec0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PhD position: Atmospheric characterisation of exoplanets with the Near-InfraRed Planet Searcher (NIRPS) </title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PhD position: Atmospheric characterisation of exoplanets with the Near-InfraRed Planet Searcher (NIRPS)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applications are invited for a research assistant (PhD student) position at the University of Geneva (&lt;a href="https://www.unige.ch/sciences/astro/en/"&gt;Department of Astronomy&lt;/a&gt;, aka the Geneva Observatory) working with &lt;a href="https://www.unige.ch/sciences/astro/exoplanets/en/team/faculty-members/ehrenreich-david/"&gt;Prof. David Ehrenreich&lt;/a&gt; on the characterisation of exoplanetary atmospheres. The successful applicant is expected to work on high-resolution spectra from the new &lt;a href="https://eso.org/public/teles-instr/lasilla/36/nirps/"&gt;Near-InfraRed Planet Searcher (NIRPS)&lt;/a&gt; at the European Southern Observatory 3.6m telescope in La Silla (Chile). The Department of Astronomy is a member of the NIRPS Consortium, which involves partners in Canada, France, Spain, Portugal, Brazil, Switerzland and at ESO. The Consortium has access to 725 nights of Guaranteed Time Observations over 5 years, out of which a substantial part will be dedicated to study the atmospheres of exoplanets. The work will involve data reduction, analysis and interpretation, as well as a participation to the observations at the 3.6m telescope in La Silla (Chile). The scientific operations of NIRPS are expected to start in October 2022. The position is funded by &lt;a href="http://nccr-planets.ch/"&gt;PlanetS&lt;/a&gt; (see below) for 4 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting: The Geneva Observatory is at the origin of the exoplanet field with the discovery of the first exoplanet around a solar-type star by Michel Mayor and Didier Queloz (Nobel prize 2019). Today, it offers one of the most vibrant environment worldwide for exoplanet research. Nearly 60 people contributes to the exoplanet team (&lt;a href="http://www.exoplanets.ch"&gt;www.exoplanets.ch&lt;/a&gt;), currently including 11 faculty members, 16 postdoctoral researchers, 16 PhD students, and 16 project staff members. Research topics include exoplanet detection, exoplanet characterization (atmospheres, interiors), planetary system dynamics, and instrumentation. Team members are directly involved into a large number of projects, including photometric instruments (CHEOPS, TESS, PLATO, NGTS), high-resolution spectrographs (HARPS, HARPS-North, NIRPS and ESPRESSO) and direct imaging (&lt;a href="/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#1b484b535e495e5b4d574f"&gt;[email protected]&lt;/a&gt;). The exoplanet team is also part of PlanetS (&lt;a href="http://www.nccr-planets.ch"&gt;www.nccr-planets.ch&lt;/a&gt;), a Swiss research network focused on exoplanetary science, which includes ~130 scientists from the Universities of Geneva, Bern, Zurich and the Zurich Institute of Technology. The successful applicant will be able to take advantage of this unique collaborative framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The University of Geneva is an equal opportunity employer committed to diversity in its workplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start date is flexible; the position could start as early as June 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duration: This is a 4-year position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salary: ~45,000 CHF/year, according to rules of the University and Canton of Geneva.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deadline: Candidates are encouraged to apply by January 31st, 2022, but later applications will be reviewed until the position is filled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Requirements: A MSc degree in astronomy, astrophysics or related fields.&lt;br /&gt;
	The successful applicant will be immersed in a team work environment, therefore good team playing abilities will be praised soft skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A curriculum vitae (2 pages max).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A cover letter (1 page max) listing the names and contact information for 2 reference persons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The above application materials should be encapsulated within a single pdf and sent to &lt;a href="/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#caaeabbca3aee4afa2b8afa4b8afa3a9a28abfa4a3adafe4a9a2"&gt;[email protected]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Up to two letters of recommendation could be sent directly to Prof. Ehrenreich by the reference persons themselves. (Recommendation letters are welcome but not mandatory to apply to the position.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;Pay CompensationSalary Min:$45000.00 (USD)</description>
      <link>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/028ded50</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:52:27 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/028ded50</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PhD Fellowship Position in Extragalactic Astronomy at the Cosmic Dawn Center, National Space Institute of Denmark</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Cosmic Dawn Center (DAWN) at the Section for Astrophysics and Atmospheric Physics at DTU Space, invites applications for a PhD Fellowship position starting in September 2021, or as soon as possible thereafter. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Project descriptions and qualifications&lt;br /&gt;
	Fellowships are intended for outstanding candidates with a background in astronomy, physics, or related technical disciplines who are interested in doing research within DAWN’s research themes: high-redshift galaxy evolution, epoch of re-ionization, first stars and galaxies, dust and ISM in the early universe and dark matter.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	The position is available for three years for candidates already holding a MSc. The successful applicants are expected to: manage and carry out their own research project, write half-year progress reports, disseminate results at conferences and through scientific articles, undertake teaching duties (up to 15% of working time) and attend PhD courses (30 ECTS). Also, a mandatory research stay during a semester abroad is to be foreseen.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Candidates should have a two-year master's degree (120 ECTS points) or a similar degree with an academic level equivalent to a two-year master's degree.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Application&lt;br /&gt;
	Please submit your online application by 25 February 2022 (Danish time).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To view the full announcement and to apply. &lt;a href="http://www.career.dtu.dk"&gt;www.career.dtu.dk&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Related URLs:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.dtu.dk/english/About/JOB-and-CAREER/vacant-positions?inst=55004786#jobFilter"&gt;Apply at the university homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Application Deadline:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Friday, February 25, 2022Selection Deadline:Friday, February 25, 2022&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Status of Position:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;p&gt;Accepting Applicants</description>
      <link>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/d1f22ce7</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:52:26 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/d1f22ce7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Postbaccalaureate Positions in Instrument Modeling, Atmospheric Modeling, and Laboratory Studies with the NASA SEEC</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Applications are now being accepted for multiple short-term postbaccalaureate research positions to support the &lt;a href="https://seec.gsfc.nasa.gov/"&gt;Sellers Exoplanet Environments Collaboration &lt;/a&gt;at NASA/Goddard Space Flight Center (NASA/GSFC) in Greenbelt, MD. The position is funded through the Southeastern Universities Research Association (SURA) and the &lt;a href="https://cresst2.umd.edu/"&gt;Center for Research and Exploration in Space Science and Technology II &lt;/a&gt;(CRESST II).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sellers Exoplanet Environments Collaboration team develops cross-disciplinary science and instrumentation models and analysis tools to assist in the exploration of exoplanet environments. The innovations and discoveries enabled here contribute to our understanding of our place in the universe and guide the development of future missions that will search for Earth-like planets around other stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Positions available with the Sellers Exoplanet Environments Collaboration span a variety of research areas. Successful candidates will be chosen to work full-time on one of the research areas listed below. Recent graduates with expertise coding in any of the below areas are invited to apply. We encourage applicants who are considering applying to a graduate program in astrophysics, planetary science, or related disciplines in the near future, and who wish to expand their research experience in the interim to also apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Area #1: Assist in developing a Python software framework to simulate spectroscopic exoplanet data acquired with a suite of novel instrument technologies. Previous experience data simulation or analysis is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Area #2: Assist in developing planet atmosphere forward model and retrieval algorithms to examine the scientific return from simulated and future data products. Results from these data simulations and analysis will facilitate design trade studies to inform technology investments and laboratory demonstrations. Previous experience in modeling or analyzing planetary atmospheres is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Area #3: Perform either 3-D climate model simulations of exoplanet atmospheres, in order to produce observables for missions like JWST and ground-based telescopes like ELTs, and/or modify a 1-D photochemistry code to apply for terrestrial and Neptune-like planets and generate observables like transit and reflection spectra. Previous experience in modeling or analyzing planetary atmospheres is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Area #4: Assist in laboratory measurements of high-temperature gas-phase species and low-temperature ices, in order to determine optical properties and improve spectral modeling tools. Previous laboratory classwork, either in chemistry or physics, is required. Technical experience with vacuum systems and FTS/FTIR would be a major advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Area #5: Assist in facilitating the development of the open-source software catalog and repository for exoplanet research software called the Exoplanet Modeling and Analysis Center (EMAC) by helping to recruit and ingest new resources, produce and advertise tutorials on new tools, and work on expanding the database structure and functionality of the catalog. Previous experience in Python coding is required, experience with CSS and Java web design and/or exoplanet modeling is a plus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;General Position Requirements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Soon or recent graduate with bachelor’s degree in astronomy, physics, or a related science or engineering discipline;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Significant experience in scientific programming (Python in particular is a major plus) OR physical/chemical laboratory work;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Available to work on-site at NASA/GSFC for 40 hours/week. Working onsite is required and/or preferable in most cases though working remotely may be possible and can be discussed as part of the hiring process; and&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Able to pass a security and background check in order to obtain a badge to access NASA/GSFC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instructions to Apply&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The positions will remain available until filled. Applications received by March 1, 2022, will receive best consideration. To apply, each applicant should send the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Your ranked top two preferences between the five areas listed above;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Curriculum Vitae;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Unofficial transcript;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A work sample in the form of either a report, poster, or journal article, along with your associated source code; and&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Two letters of reference arranged to be sent directly from your referees by the application deadline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Application materials should be submitted to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SEEC Post-Baccalaureate Research Assistant&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Via e-mail to &lt;a href="/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#563d37223e33243f38337825783b353d3333163837253778313920"&gt;[email protected]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salary and benefits are competitive, commensurate with experience and qualifications. The desired start date is in the range June - September 2022, with an initial employment term of 1 year that may be extended for 1 additional year contingent on performance and availability of funds. Financial assistance for relocation expenses is possible and can be discussed as part of the onboarding process. All students, faculty, and staff are required to be vaccinated against COVID. Proof of full vaccination will be required before the start of employment through CRESST II at NASA/GSFC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about the proposed research, contact Dr. Avi Mandell (&lt;a href="/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#59382f30773438373d3c35351937382a38773e362f"&gt;[email protected]&lt;/a&gt;). For information on CRESST II or SURA, contact Ms. Carolyn Wilson (&lt;a href="/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#4e2d3927223d21200e3d3b3c2f60213c29"&gt;[email protected]&lt;/a&gt;). SURA is an equal opportunity employer and welcomes all to apply. EOE/M/F/D/V.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Related URLs:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://seec.gsfc.nasa.gov/"&gt;Sellers Exoplanet Environments Collaboration (SEEC)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://cresst2.umd.edu/"&gt;CRESST II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Application Deadline:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Tuesday, March 1, 2022Selection Deadline:Wednesday, June 1, 2022&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Status of Position:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;p&gt;Accepting Applicants</description>
      <link>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/081d0db5</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 13:10:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/081d0db5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PhD positions in Astronomy and Astrophysics at Warwick University</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The University of Warwick Astronomy and Astrophysics group is seeking talented PhD applicants for our new &lt;a href="https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/physics/research/astro/vacancies/prize/"&gt;Warwick Prize Scholarships&lt;/a&gt; in Astrophysics. Applications are due by January 14th 2022. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scholarships are open to national and international applicants and all are welcome to apply. We expect to offer around 10 funded PhD places in this round, including places funded via direct research grants, UK research agency support, and university allocations. All projects offered will provide a full stipend plus allocations for travel and computing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Projects span a range of research areas including exoplanet discovery, characterisation and formation, transients and explosive astrophysical phenomena, white dwarfs and planetary remnants, and stellar populations. Details on potential projects and the application process can be found here: &lt;a href="https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/physics/research/astro/postgraduate/"&gt;https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/physics/research/astro/postgraduate/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applicants are encouraged to contact the project supervisors for further information on the projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warwick is an internationally recognised centre of excellence in &lt;a href="https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/physics/research/astro/research/"&gt;research&lt;/a&gt;. Our group is involved in many major ground and space-based projects, including the Sloan Digital Sky Survey, ESA's CHEOPS satellite and upcoming PLATO mission, the Next Generation Transit Survey (NGTS), and the Gravitational-wave Optical Transient Observer (GOTO).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both the Physics Department and the University of Warwick hold Athena SWAN Silver awards, a national initiative to promote gender equality for all staff and students. Our Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics group also hosts monthly &lt;a href="https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/physics/research/astro/seminars/equitea/"&gt;equitea&lt;/a&gt; forums to break down barriers faced by all under-represented groups in science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the University of Warwick, we strongly value equity, diversity and inclusion, and encourage applications from all under-represented groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information on the Warwick Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics Group can be found here: &lt;a href="https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/physics/research/astro/"&gt;https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/physics/research/astro/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
Pay CompensationStipend:$20970.00 (USD)Compensation Notes:Stipend is annual and tax-free, increasing with inflation. Additional paid teaching work is available and encouraged.</description>
      <link>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/8616abdf</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 01:35:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/8616abdf</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PhD positions in Prague: theory, observation, instrumentation</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are offering multiple 4-year PhD positions in Prague, Czech Republic, in the fields of Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics, Astroparticle Physics, Cosmology, Gravity, Mathematical Physics, String Theory, and Atomic and Molecular Physics. The areas of research include theory, observation, and instrumentation. The list of available projects is at &lt;a href="http://physicsphd.cz/f1"&gt;http://physicsphd.cz/f1&lt;/a&gt;. This list of projects will be finalized by December 5 2021 when we will also open the Application form for submissions. The application deadline is January 15 2022 for positions beginning in the Fall semester of 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PhD thesis research will be conducted at one of the participating institutions in Prague: Charles University (Institute of Theoretical Physics and Astronomical Institute) and Czech Academy of Sciences (Institute of Physics, Astronomical Institute, Institute of Mathematics, and Nuclear Physics Institute). The PhD degrees are awarded by Charles University. The positions are funded by a combination of government stipend, individual grants (national or EU), and institutional fellowships. The positions are open to candidates of any nationality. Our PhD program is international with majority of students coming from abroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benefits depend on the type of the working contract, but all PhD students receive subsidized meals, possibility of staying in student dormitories, and free "Czech as foreign language" classes. There are no fees or tuition for PhD students. Prague remains cheaper than other comparable European cities while offering similar level of comforts and entertainments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information and application procedure, please see &lt;a href="http://physicsphd.cz/f1"&gt;http://physicsphd.cz/f1&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Application Deadline:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Saturday, January 15, 2022Selection Deadline:Saturday, April 30, 2022&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Status of Position:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;p&gt;No Status Given (Opted Out)</description>
      <link>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/0d2e5b3a</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 17:07:58 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobregister.aas.org/ad/0d2e5b3a</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
